Guide to the John Flournoy Montgomery Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
John Flournoy Montgomery papers
1933-1939
MS 353
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
2.5
(6 boxes)
The papers consist of correspondence documenting Montgomery's role asambassador to Hungary. Included are letters from prominent Hungarians and members of the U.S. diplomatic corps.
Montgomery, John Flournoy, 1878-1954
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of James M. Osborne.
Scope and Contents
The Montgomery Papers consist of correspondence, 1933-1939. The letters are to and from John Flournoy Montgomery (1878-1954) while he was U.S. Ambassador to Hungary. There are letters of prominent Hungarians as well as members of the U.S. diplomatic corps.
The letters are bound in ten volumes and are arranged both chronologically and alphabetically.
The John F. Montgomery Papers were given to Yale University Library by James M. Osborne.
Biographical / Historical
John Flournoy Montgomery was born in Sedalia, Missouri on September 20, 1878. He held positions in various companies concerned with the milk industry. From 1933-1941, Montgomery served as United States ambassador to Hungary. He died on November 7, 1954.
Europe; Hungary -- Foreign relations; Diplomatic and consular service, American; United States -- Foreign relations -- Hungary; Diplomats; Barkley, Alben William, 1877-1956; Bullitt, William C. (William Christian), 1891-1967; Daniels, Josephus, 1862-1948; Davies, Joseph Edward, 1876-1958; Horthy, Miklós, nagybányai, 1868-1957; Hull, Cordell, 1871-1955; Lane, Arthur Bliss, 1894-1956; McAdoo, W. G. (William Gibbs), 1863-1941; Messersmith, George S. (George Strausser), 1883-1960; Montgomery, John Flournoy, 1878-1954; Roosevelt, Kermit, 1889-1943; Roosevelt, Nicholas, 1893-1982; Welles, Sumner, 1892-1961; Wickersham, George W. (George Woodward), 1858-1936
- Inventory, 1933-1939
  - Volume I - Budapest Diplomatic Corps Exchanges, 1933-1937
    - Correspondence with various members of the diplomatic corps in Budapest:
      - Bailen, Count Carlos de (Box 1)
      - Beauverger, Baron Edmond de (Box 1)
      - Behic, Erkin (Box 1)
      - Busk, Douglas (Box 1)
      - Colonna, Don Ascanio (Box 1)
      - Gracie, S. de Souza-Leao (Box 1)
      - Grigorcea, Basile (Box 1)
      - Hennet, Leopold (Box 1)
      - Knox, Sir Geoffrey (Box 1)
      - Lalaing, Count Jacques de (Box 1)
      - Maugras, Gaston (Box 1)
      - Nyyssonen, Jean (Box 1)
      - Neustadter-Sturmer, Odo Baron (Box 1)
      - Ramsay, Sir Patrick (Box 1)
      - Scilianos, Demetrios (Box 1)
    - Correspondence with prominent Hungarians in official life and otherwise:
      - Albrecht, Archduke (Box 1)
      - Andrassy, Count Emanuel (Box 1)
      - Apor, Baron Gabriel (Box 1)
      - Balasy, Anthony (Box 1)
      - Barczy, Istvan (Box 1)
      - Beldy, Colonel Alajos (Box 1)
      - Bethlen, Count Stephen (Box 1)
      - Bohm, Ferenc (Box 1)
      - Dohnanyi, Erno (Box 1)
      - Eckhardt, Dr. Tibor (Box 1)
      - Edvi-Illes, Captain Lajos (Box 1)
      - Forgach, Countess Hanna (Box 1)
      - Forgach, Count John (Box 1)
      - Forstner, Dr. Paul (Box 1)
      - Ghika, George de (Box 1)
      - Havas Dr. Eugene (Box 1)
      - Homan, Dr. Balint (Box 1)
      - Horthy, Nicholas (Regent of Hungary) (Box 1)
      - Kalliwoda, Miss Olga K. (Box 1)
      - Kallay, Nicholas de (Box 1)
      - Lazar, Andor (Box 1)
      - Ottlik, George de (Box 1)
      - Penenyi, John (Box 1)
      - Perenyi, Baron Sigismund (Box 1)
      - Rakovszky, Ivan de (Box 1)
      - Scholtz, Captain Andre (Box 1)
      - Sibrik, Major George (Box 1)
      - Solyom, Jeno (Box 1)
      - Teleki, Court Paul (Box 1)
      - Varga, Stephen (Box 1)
      - Vladar, Dr. Ervin (Box 1)
      - Winchkler, Dr. Stephen de (Box 1)
      - Zichy, Count Erno (Box 1)
      - Zichy, Countess Raphael (Box 1)
  - Volume II - Correspondence with prominent Hungarians and diplomatic corps, 1938-1939
    - Correspondence with prominent Hungarians in official life and otherwise:
      - Algya-Pap, Lt. Col. Zoltan (Box 1)
      - Apor, Baron Gabor (Box 1)
      - Balasy Anton (Box 1)
      - Balogh F. (Box 1)
      - Barczy, Istvan de (Box 1)
      - Beldy, General (Box 1)
      - Bessenyei, Zeno (Box 1)
      - Daranyi, Bela de (Box 1)
      - Daranyi, Kalman (Box 1)
      - Dohnanyi, Erno (Box 1)
      - Eckhardt, Tibor and Ellen (Box 1)
      - Ghika George de (Box 1)
      - Grosz, Professor Emile de (Box 1)
      - Gyulay, Dr. Louis (Box 1)
      - Hapsburgs Archduke Albrecht (Box 1)
      - Hatvany, Andrew (Box 1)
      - Havas, Eugene (Box 1)
      - Hohenlohe, Prince Francis (Box 1)
      - Homan, Balint (Box 1)
      - Horthy, Nicholas (Regent of Hungary) (Box 1)
      - lmredy, Bela (Box 1)
      - Kallay, Mr. & Mrs. Milos de (Box 1)
      - Kanya, Kalman de (Box 1)
      - Kelemen, Krizosztom (Box 1)
      - Kerpel Dr. Eugene (Box 1)
      - Kiss, Geza de (Box 1)
      - Klebelsberg, Count Kuno (Box 1)
      - Lazar, Dr. Andor de (Box 1)
      - Marffy-Mantuano, Dr. Tamas (Box 1)
      - Olah Gustav (Box 1)
      - Ottlik, George (Box 1)
      - Pallavicini, Marquise de (Box 1)
      - Pelenyi, John (Box 1)
      - Quandt, Richard (Box 1)
      - Rakovszky, Dr. Ivan (Box 1)
      - Scholtz, Captain Andrew (Box 1)
      - Sigray, Anton (Box 1)
      - Szapary, Count Antal (Box 1)
      - Szechenyi, Count Charles (Box 1)
      - Szechenyi Gladys (Box 1)
      - Szechenyi, Lajos and George (Box 1)
      - Teleki, Count Paul (Box 1)
      - Uray (Box 1)
      - Vertesy (Box 1)
      - Villani, Baran Lajos (Box 1)
      - Zichy, Count Janos (Box 1)
    - Budapest diplomatic corps exchanges:
      - Bailen Count de (Box 1)
      - Beauverger, Baron Edmond de (Box 1)
      - Bossy Raoul (Box 1)
      - Colonna, Don Ascanio dei principi (Box 1)
      - Erkin, Behic (Box 1)
      - Gracie, M.S. Sousa de (Box 1)
      - Kobr, Milos (Box 1)
      - MacKensen, Hans George von (Box 1)
      - Marei A. (Box 1)
      - Nepveu, R.C.T. Roosmale (Box 1)
      - O'Malley, Owen St. Clair (Box 1)
      - Orlowski, Leon (Box 1)
      - Plotnikoff, Victor (Box 1)
      - Ramsay, Sir Patrick (Box 1)
      - Stoiloff, Dr. Stoil C. (Box 1)
      - Vinci, di: Conte Luigi Crasio Vinci Gigliucci (Box 1)
      - Vouktchevitch, Alexandre (Box 1)
  - Volume III - Foreign Service personnel exchanges, part one:, 1933-1937
    - Ackerson, Garret G., Jr. (Box 2)
    - Albright, Edward (Box 2)
    - Benton, J. Webb (Box 2)
    - Bingham, Robert W. (Box 2)
    - Buffum, David (Box 2)
    - Bullitt, William C. (Box 2)
    - Byington, Homer (Box 2)
    - Carr, Wilbur J. (Box 2)
    - Cudahy John (Box 2)
    - Dodd, William E. (Box 2)
    - DuBois, Coert (Box 2)
    - Dunn, James C. (Box 2)
    - English, Robert (Box 2)
    - Erhardt, John G. (Box 2)
    - Flack, Joseph (Box 2)
    - Frazer, Robert (Box 2)
    - Harris Ernest L. (Box 2)
    - Holmes, Julius C. (Box 2)
    - Honaker, Samuel W. (Box 2)
    - Huddle, J. Klahr (Box 2)
    - Jenkins, Douglas (Box 2)
    - Johnson, Hartwell (Box 2)
    - Lane, Arthur Bliss (Box 2)
    - Lee, Frank C. (Box 2)
    - Long, Breckinridge (Box 2)
    - MacVeagh, Lincoln (Box 2)
    - Michael, Louis G. (Box 2)
    - Moffat, J. Pierrepont (Box 2)
    - Moore R. Walton (Box 2)
    - Morgan, John Heath (Box 2)
    - Murray Wallace S. (Box 2)
    - Messersmith George S. (Box 2)
    - Owsley Alvin W. (Box 2)
  - Volume IV - Foreign Service personnel exchanges, part two:
    - Phillips, William (Box 2)
    - Pinkerton, Lowell C. (Box 2)
    - Riggs, B. Heath (Box 2)
    - Riley, Major Lowell M. (Box 2)
    - Schoenfeld, Rudolf E. (Box 2)
    - Schott, W. W. (Box 2)
    - Scott, John W. (Box 2)
    - Shallenberger, Colonel Martin C. (Box 2)
    - Shaw, G. Howland (Box 2)
    - Shipley, Ruth B. (Box 2)
    - Steere, Loyd V. (Box 2)
    - Stewart, James B. (Box 2)
    - Strauss, James Isidor (Box 2)
    - Travers, Howard K. (Box 2)
    - White John C. (Box 2)
    - Wilson Charles S. (Box 2)
    - Wilson, Orme (Box 2)
    - Wilson, Thomas M. (Box 2)
    - Wright, J. Butler (Box 2)
    - Young, James R. (Box 2)
  - Volume IV - Correspondence with people in public life in U.S.:, 1933-1937
    - Barkley, Senator Alben W. (Box 2)
    - Barton, Bruce (Box 2)
    - Burnham, George (Box 2)
    - Davis, Joseph (Box 2)
    - Davis, Chester C. (Box 2)
    - Grady, Henry F. (Box 2)
    - Jones, Robert Tyre, Jr. (Box 2)
    - Manly, Basil (Box 2)
    - McAdoo, William G. (Box 2)
    - O'Connor, John F. T. (Box 2)
    - Peek, George N. (Box 2)
    - Pittman, Key (Box 2)
    - Standley, William H. (Box 2)
    - Stones Captain and Mrs. Willis S. (Box 2)
    - Uhl, Byron H. (Box 2)
  - Volume V - Foreign Service personnel exchanges, part one:, 1938-1939
    - Ackerson, Garrett G., Jr. (Box 3)
    - Biddle, Anthony J. Drexel, Jr. (Box 3)
    - Gigelow, Donald (Box 3)
    - Boals, Gordon P. (Box 3)
    - Bucknell, Howard, Jr. (Box 3)
    - Buffum, David H. (Box 3)
    - Byington, Homer M. (Box 3)
    - Carr Wilbur J. (Box 3)
    - Coe, Robert D. (Box 3)
    - Coulter, Eliot B. (Box 3)
    - Cox, Raymond E. (Box 3)
    - Cudahy, John (Box 3)
    - Daniels, Josephus (Box 3)
    - Davies Joseph E. (Box 3)
    - Donald, George K. (Box 3)
    - Dunn, James C. (Box 3)
    - English, Robert (Box 3)
    - Erhardt, John G. (Box 3)
    - Frost, Arthur C. (Box 3)
    - Fullerton, Hugh S. (Box 3)
    - Gilbert, Prentiss (Box 3)
    - Gordon, George A. (Box 3)
    - Gotlieb, Bernard (Box 3)
    - Grady, Henry F. (Box 3)
    - Gunther, Franklin Mott (Box 3)
    - Hull, Cordell (Box 3)
    - Harrison, Leland (Box 3)
    - Hibbard, Frederick P. (Box 3)
    - Huddle, J. Klahr (Box 3)
    - Huston, Cloyce K. (Box 3)
    - Ives, Ernest L. (Box 3)
    - Joyce, Robert P. (Box 3)
    - Keith, Gerald (Box 3)
    - Lane, Arthur Bliss (Box 3)
    - Lee, Frank C. (Box 3)
    - Lee, Lt. Colonel Raymond E. (Box 3)
    - Linnell, Irving N. (Box 3)
    - Linthicum, Walter J. (Box 3)
  - Volume VI - Foreign Service personnel exchanges, part two:, 1938-1939
    - Macatee, Robert B. (Box 3)
    - MacMurray, John V. A. (Box 3)
    - MaDonne, John H. (Box 3)
    - Maher, Dale W. (Box 3)
    - Messersmith, George S. (Box 3)
    - Michael, Louis G. (Box 3)
    - Moffat, J. Pierrepont (Box 3)
    - Moore, R Walton (Box 3)
    - Morgan, John H. (Box 3)
    - Morris, Leland B. (Box 3)
    - Murphy, Robert D. (Box 3)
    - Owsley, Alvin M. (Box 3)
    - Peck, William L. (Box 3)
    - Phillips, William (Box 3)
    - Plitt, Edwin A. (Box 3)
    - Ramsay, Hugh F. (Box 3)
    - Reber, Samuel (Box 3)
    - Reed, Charles S. (Box 3)
    - Riley, Major Lowell M. (Box 3)
    - Rogers, Alan (Box 3)
    - Sayre, Francis B. (Box 3)
    - Schoenfeld, H. F. Arthur (Box 3)
    - Schoenfeld, Rudolph (Box 3)
    - Schott, William W. (Box 3)
    - Shallenberger, Colonel Martin C. (Box 3)
    - Shaw, G. Howland (Box 3)
    - Sholes, Walter H. (Box 3)
    - Stewart, James B. (Box 3)
    - Squire, Paul C. (Box 3)
    - Summerlin, George T. (Box 3)
    - Travers, Howard K. (Box 3)
    - Warren, Avra M. (Box 3)
    - Warren, Fletcher (Box 3)
    - Wendell, Alexander W. (Box 3)
    - Welles, Sumner (Box 3)
    - Wiley, John C. (Box 3)
    - Wiley, Samuel H. (Box 3)
    - Wilson, Edwin C. (Box 3)
    - Wilson, Hugh R. (Box 3)
    - Wilson, Orme (Box 3)
    - Wilson, Tevis (Box 3)
    - Wilson, Warden McK. (Box 3)
    - Wright, J. Butler (Box 3)
  - Volume VII - Personal correspondence, part one:, 1933-1937
    - Alexander, A. M. (Box 4)
    - Amos, Mrs. Benjamin (Box 4)
    - Arkell, Bartlett (Box 4)
    - Arrington, Mrs. Olive P. (Box 4)
    - Atterholt, A. W. (Box 4)
    - Avery, L. (Box 4)
    - Baldwin, C. B. (Box 4)
    - Ball, Dr. O. F. (Box 4)
    - Barnes, Dr. Robert (Box 4)
    - Bendix Products Corp. (Box 4)
    - Blackshear, Charles L. (Box 4)
    - Blaine, James G. (Box 4)
    - Blair, Floyd C. (Box 4)
    - Boody, David (Box 4)
    - Boody, Edgar (Box 4)
    - Boross, Colonel Eugene (Box 4)
    - Brent, Theodore (Box 4)
    - British Broadcasting Corp. (Box 4)
    - Brown, Stewart (Box 4)
    - Bruce, Benjamin (Box 4)
    - Buchman, Frank W. D. (Box 4)
    - Buckley, Harry (Box 4)
    - Burlintson, John (Box 4)
    - Bush, Wallace (Box 4)
    - Bustabo, Mrs. A. J. (Box 4)
    - Capital & Counties Industrial Trust (Box 4)
    - Chambers, Frank W. (Box 4)
    - Chambers, Peter (Box 4)
    - Cheatham, Miss Kitty (Box 4)
    - Cholnoky, Tibor de (Box 4)
    - Cobb, Chandler (Box 4)
    - Colebaugs Charles (Box 4)
    - Cook, J. Todd (Box 4)
    - Cortisoz, Royal (Box 4)
    - Curtis, Mrs. Carroll P. (Box 4)
    - Daniels, Jonathan (Box 4)
    - Davis, Henry (Box 4)
    - Doubleday Doran (Box 4)
    - Earle, George H., II (Box 4)
    - Earle, George H., III (Box 4)
    - Farrand, Beatrix (Box 4)
    - Fedde, A. S. (Box 4)
    - Ferguson, Mrs. Meade (Box 4)
    - Fletcher, Frederic C. (Box 4)
    - Fowler, Mrs. Frederick (Box 4)
    - Frankerberg, Theodore T. (Box 4)
    - Franklin Bibliophile Society (Box 4)
    - Frost, Norman B. (Box 4)
    - Glazier, Major F. Bedford (Box 4)
    - Goldsborough, Laird S. (Box 4)
    - Goldwater, R. A. (Box 4)
    - Goodwillie, Malcolm (Box 4)
    - Goodyear Tire & Rubber Export Co. (Box 4)
    - Gorrell, Frank E. (Box 4)
    - Green, Allen P. (Box 4)
    - Green, De Witt (Box 4)
    - Griffiths Edward (Box 4)
    - Griggs, David (Box 4)
    - Gunther, John (Box 4)
    - Hackett, Raymond E. (Box 4)
    - Hales Testimonial Fund (Box 4)
    - Halmi, Mrs. A. L. (Box 4)
    - Hammond C.S. & Co. (Box 4)
    - Hansen, Louis (Box 4)
    - Harris & Ewing (Box 4)
    - Hartigan John (Box 4)
    - Hettler, Oscar (Box 4)
    - Higbie, Robert W., Jr. (Box 4)
    - Hill, Ira (Box 4)
    - Horwath, Edmund J. (Box 4)
    - Hubsch, Bernice (Box 4)
    - Hughes, Miss Margaret Lee (Box 4)
    - Hyde. James H. (Box 4)
    - Ineson, Stanley B. (Box 4)
    - Ineson, Thomas P. (Box 4)
    - International Press-Cutting Bureau (Box 4)
    - Isham, Lincoln (Box 4)
    - Johnston, James (Box 4)
    - Juhasz, Emile W. (Box 4)
    - Katz, Ernest Fritz (Box 4)
    - Keeler, O. B. (Box 4)
    - Kerpel, Dr. Eugene (Box 4)
    - Kiley, Henry P. (Box 4)
    - Kremer, James Bruce (Box 4)
  - Volume VIII - Personal correspondence, part two:, 1933-1937
    - Lee, Charles T. (Box 4)
    - Lee, Frank C. (Box 4)
    - Lee, Robert T. (Box 4)
    - Lemon, James (Box 4)
    - Lewis, Earle (Box 4)
    - Life Saving Service of N.Y. (Box 4)
    - Liggetts Drug Store (Box 4)
    - Loeb, Howard A. (Box 4)
    - Luca, Guiseppe de (Box 4)
    - Lynn, Meda (Box 4)
    - MacRride, Colonel H. D. (Box 4)
    - MacDonald, Robert M. (Box 4)
    - MacDonald, Mr. and Mrs. W. H. (Box 4)
    - Mallon, Jackie (Box 4)
    - Manchester Winter Sports Club (Box 4)
    - Margaret Island (Box 4)
    - Martin, Harry H. (Box 4)
    - Maull, Baldwin (Box 4)
    - Maxwell, Lee W. (Box 4)
    - McNeil, Archibald (Box 4)
    - McReynolds, Sam (Box 4)
    - Meili, Ernest H. (Box 4)
    - Menninger, Dr. Karl (Box 4)
    - Mills, Helen Harrison (Box 4)
    - Moeller, Edmund (Box 4)
    - Montgomery, George S. (Box 4)
    - Montgomery, Lee (Box 4)
    - Moore, R. Walton (Box 4)
    - Morgan, Sherley W. (Box 4)
    - Morgan, W. Forbes (Box 4)
    - Murphy, Frederick E. (Box 4)
    - National Geographic Society (Box 4)
    - Newell, Mrs. J. P. (Box 4)
    - New Yorker, The (Box 4)
    - Norris, Beverly A. (Box 4)
    - O'connor, Miss Anna K. (Box 4)
    - Odom, Mrs. Helen Hale (Box 4)
    - Ogletree, Tigner (Box 4)
    - Pattullo, George (Box 4)
    - Pearson, Frank (Box 4)
    - Pell, Robert Thompson (Box 4)
    - Politzer, Jerome (Box 4)
    - Porter, William J. (Box 4)
    - Powell, Captain T. W. (Box 4)
    - Price, Ollie (Box 4)
    - Quilhot, William K. (Box 4)
    - Raith, Miss Lillie (Box 4)
    - Read, Harlan Eugene (Box 4)
    - Reed, Albert M. (Box 4)
    - Reschofsky, Alexander (Box 4)
    - Robinson, Charles E. (Box 4)
    - Rogers, Dr. Edward J. (Box 4)
    - Roosevelt, Mrs. J. West (Box 4)
    - Roosevelt, Kermit (Box 4)
    - Roosevelt, Nicholas (Box 4)
    - Rosseter, Mrs. John H. (Box 4)
    - Rota, F. C. (Box 4)
    - Schilder, Mrs. Harold (Box 4)
    - Schoffelmayer, Victor H. (Box 4)
    - Schwarz, Earl G. (Box 4)
    - Scott, Charles V. (Box 4)
    - Sharpless, Casper P. (Box 4)
    - Shaw, Arthur (Box 4)
    - Shimer, Josephine D. (Box 4)
    - Singers Mortimer M. (Box 4)
    - Sneed, Robert C. (Box 4)
    - Snitzler, John T. (Box 4)
    - South, Major T. (Box 4)
    - Stanley, William (Box 4)
    - Stebbins, Robert H. (Box 4)
    - Stevenson, Dr. J. Ross (Box 4)
    - Stuart, Elbridge A. (Box 4)
    - Stuarts, Graham H. (Box 4)
    - Swifts, H. E. (Box 4)
    - Szekely, I. (Box 4)
    - Taylor, Henry C. (Box 4)
    - Terry, William (Box 4)
    - Thomas, Fred W. (Box 4)
    - Thompson, R. E. (Box 4)
    - Towers, Frederic N. (Box 4)
    - Townsend, Robert (Box 4)
    - Tyler, Royall (Box 4)
    - Van Bomel, L. A. (Box 4)
    - Volz, Carl W. (Box 4)
    - Vonhoffmann, Mrs. W. R. (Box 4)
    - Walsh, William (Box 4)
    - Webster Motor Sales Co., Inc. (Box 4)
    - Weeds J. Spencer (Box 4)
    - Wehrhane, Henry H. (Box 4)
    - White, R. T. (Box 4)
    - Whitehill, Clarence (Box 4)
    - Wickersham, George W. (Box 4)
    - Williams, Edwin Moss (Box 4)
    - Wolff, Harry (Box 4)
    - Y.M.C.A. (Box 4)
    - Youngs Elizabeth (Box 4)
    - Zell, Lucien T. (Box 4)
  - Volume IX - Personal correspondence, part one:, 1938-1939
    - Arkell, Bartlett (Box 5)
    - Atterholts, Mr. A. W. (Box 5)
    - Amos, Mrs. (Box 5)
    - Arms, John Taylor (Box 5)
    - Bandholtz, Mrs. Inez Clair (Box 5)
    - Barrow, Flora B. (Box 5)
    - Baverstock, Harvey J. (Box 5)
    - Best, Robert H. (Box 5)
    - Boczko, Laszlo (Box 5)
    - Bohland, Gustav (Box 5)
    - Bolton, R. P. (Box 5)
    - Boody, Edgar (Box 5)
    - Boross, Colonel Eugene (Box 5)
    - Bottome, Harry Howard (Box 5)
    - Browns, Thomas R. (Box 5)
    - Bruce, Henry J. (Box 5)
    - Chambers, Frank W. (Box 5)
    - Chance, Wade (Box 5)
    - Chapman, John F. (Box 5)
    - Chase, P. Adele (Box 5)
    - Cheatham, Kitty (Box 5)
    - Clare, James L. (Box 5)
    - Cobb, Candler (Box 5)
    - Colebaugh, Charles (Box 5)
    - Cortissoz, Royal (Box 5)
    - Cravath, Paul (Box 5)
    - Crump, Stephen (Box 5)
    - Cummins, Joseph J. (Box 5)
    - Davis, Chester C. (Box 5)
    - Davis Howard (Box 5)
    - Davis, Norma (Box 5)
    - Day and Meyer (Box 5)
    - Denham, S. J. (Box 5)
    - Dubois, Dr. Francis (Box 5)
    - Dunnick, John (Box 5)
    - Farley, James A. (Box 5)
    - Fletcher, Mr. and Mrs. F. C. (Box 5)
    - Flournoy, Dr. Henri (Box 5)
    - Frankenberg, T. T. (Box 5)
    - Franklin, John (Box 5)
    - Fraser, Louise M. (Box 5)
    - Frost, Norman B. (Box 5)
    - Gay, Winifred (Box 5)
    - Glasier, Major F. Bedford (Box 5)
    - Goldwater, Robert (Box 5)
    - Gorrell, Frank E. (Box 5)
    - Goodwillie, Malcolm (Box 5)
    - Griggs, Mr. Ara A. (Box 5)
    - Gutman, William (Box 5)
    - Hackett, Raymond E. (Box 5)
    - Haller, Dr. Henry S. (Box 5)
    - Hamlin, Irene W. (Box 5)
    - Henry, Oliver B. (Box 5)
    - Herring, Albert C. (Box 5)
    - Hettler, Oscar (Box 5)
    - Heydt, Henry Herman (Box 5)
    - Higbie, Robert W., Jr. (Box 5)
    - Horwath, Edmund J. (Box 5)
    - Hoskins, Halford L. (Box 5)
    - House, Charles L. (Box 5)
    - Howland, Dr. Wells (Box 5)
    - Hubbell, George L. (Box 5)
    - Huberman John (Box 5)
    - Hughes, Austin V. (Box 5)
    - Hulse, J. G. (Box 5)
    - Hutter, Paul (Box 5)
    - Hyde, James H. (Box 5)
    - Ineson, Stanley B. (Box 5)
    - Isham, Lincoln (Box 5)
    - Jamner, Jacob Suter (Box 5)
    - Johnston, James M. (Box 5)
    - Juhasz, Emile W. (Box 5)
    - Keim, George H. (Box 5)
    - Kennedy, Joseph P. (Box 5)
    - Kingsley, Richard H. (Box 5)
    - Kingsley, Zell (Box 5)
    - Knight, Emlen (Box 5)
    - Lackey, Rear Admiral H. E. (Box 5)
    - Lamont, Thomas W. (Box 5)
    - Lancaster, Mrs. Charles (Box 5)
    - Leader, Williams, B. C. (Box 5)
    - Lee, C. T. (Box 5)
    - Lemon James H. (Box 5)
    - Lewis Earle (Box 5)
    - Lienau, Mrs. Paul (Box 5)
    - Litton, Mrs. Ida (Box 5)
    - Llobet, Jose Manuel (Box 5)
    - Loeb, Howard A. (Box 5)
    - Lowe, Theodore (Box 5)
    - Luca, Guiseppe de (Box 5)
  - Volume X - Personal correspondence, part two:, 1938-1939
    - Mallon, Jack (Box 6)
    - MacDonald, John M. (Box 6)
    - MacDonald, Robert M. (Box 6)
    - MacDonald, W. R. (Box 6)
    - Manchester, Printing Company (Box 6)
    - Marsh, John (Box 6)
    - Marshall, H. G. (Box 6)
    - Martin Louis (Box 6)
    - Martin, W. G. (Box 6)
    - Mason, Frenwiok & Lawrence (Box 6)
    - McAdoo, W. G. (Box 6)
    - McCabe, Colonel E. R. W. (Box 6)
    - McGill, J. J. (Box 6)
    - McGrath, John (Box 6)
    - McLeod, Freddie (Box 6)
    - McNeil, Arch (Box 6)
    - Meadows, M. R. (Box 6)
    - Meily, John Jams (Box 6)
    - Meljohn, Alfred (Box 6)
    - Memminger, Catalina (Box 6)
    - Menz, Herman (Box 6)
    - Michael, Mrs. Josey (Box 6)
    - Minthorn, R. E. (Box 6)
    - Missouri, State Historical Society (Box 6)
    - Montfort, Nelson (Box 6)
    - Montgomery, George S. (Box 6)
    - Montgomery, John Z. (Box 6)
    - Montgomery, Lee (Box 6)
    - Morgan, Richard and Diana (Box 6)
    - Morgan, Sherley (Box 6)
    - Morse, Cabot (Box 6)
    - Moss, R. S. (Box 6)
    - Muller, Edmund (Box 6)
    - National, Geographic Society (Box 6)
    - Norris, Beverly (Box 6)
    - O'Connell, M. Fred (Box 6)
    - Oester, Johann (Box 6)
    - O'Mahoney, Miss (Box 6)
    - Padelford, Norman J. (Box 6)
    - Parsons, Geoffrey (Box 6)
    - Pasternik, Joseph J. (Box 6)
    - Pearson, Frank M (Box 6)
    - Pierce, Leslie D. (Box 6)
    - Pinkney, Albert (Box 6)
    - Porter, william J. (Box 6)
    - Reynolds, Senator Robert R. (Box 6)
    - Reed, Albert M. (Box 6)
    - Reichert, Dr. Irwing F. (Box 6)
    - Richardson, W.L. (Box 6)
    - Roberts, W. E. (Box 6)
    - Robbins, Edward H. (Box 6)
    - Robinson, Charles E. (Box 6)
    - Roosevelt, Nicholas (Box 6)
    - Rorapaugh, E. A. (Box 6)
    - Rosseter, Mrs. John H. (Box 6)
    - Ruhr, Mrs. Louis J. (Box 6)
    - Schilder, Mrs. Miriam (Box 6)
    - Schott, Albert H. (Box 6)
    - Shaw, Arthur (Box 6)
    - Shipley, Ruth B. (Box 6)
    - Singer, Mortimer W. (Box 6)
    - Small, J. H. and Sons (Box 6)
    - Smiths, Elizabeth (Box 6)
    - Smith, F. M. (Box 6)
    - Sneed, Robert (Box 6)
    - Snitzler, John T. (Box 6)
    - Speyer, James B. (Box 6)
    - Stabler, Jordan Herbert (Box 6)
    - Stanley, William (Box 6)
    - Steer, Lloyd V. (Box 6)
    - Stevens, Francis B. (Box 6)
    - Stone, Jack (Box 6)
    - Storke, Thomas M. (Box 6)
    - Stuart, Elbridge A. (Box 6)
    - Swift, Ernest (Box 6)
    - Szekely, Mr. I. (Box 6)
    - Terry, Willard (Box 6)
    - Thompson, George (Box 6)
    - Towers, Frederic N. (Box 6)
    - Tyler Royall (Box 6)
    - Van Bomel, Leroy A. (Box 6)
    - Vidmer, Richard (Box 6)
    - Virus Limited, Inc. (Box 6)
    - Walsh, David I. (Box 6)
    - Wheeler, Burton K. (Box 6)
    - Walker, Frank C. (Box 6)
    - Wear, D. Walker (Box 6)
    - Westminister College (Box 6)
    - Williams, Basil C. (Box 6)
    - Williams, Edmund (Box 6)
    - Williams, Edwin Moss (Box 6)
    - Winchester, Tarleton (Box 6)
    - Wolff, Miriam (Box 6)
    - Wolvin, Mrs. Roy Mitchell (Box 6)
    - Wright, Raymond E. (Box 6)
    - Zell, Lucien T. (Box 6)